在这个模块中
in this module
我们将看看如何编写自动化
we're going to look at how to write automated
长生不老药中的测试
tests in elixir
但这里有一些事情
but here's some things
我们不会在这个模块中做
we're not going to do in this module
我们不会试图说服你测试是
we're not going to try to convince you that testing is
重要的是，我们假设您已经知道
important we assume you already know that
我们也不去
we're also not going
如果你不是，让你感到羞耻
to shame you if you're not
做洗手间和发展
doing restroom and development
或者没有 100% 的测试覆盖率
or don't have 100% test coverage
事实上，我们根本不会宣扬测试教条
in fact we're not going to preach testing dogma at all
我们假设
we're going to assume
你已经使用了一个单元测试框架
you've used a unit testing framework in
另一种语言
another language
并且您想知道如何在 elixir 中进行测试
and you want to know how to test in elixir
现在我们在处理程序的底部有这段代码
right now we have this code at the bottom of handler
向句柄函数发送请求
that sends request to the handle function
并打印出响应
and prints out the responses
因此，当我们在 ix 会话中重新编译调查处理程序时
so when we recompile survey handler in an ix session
该代码运行，我们看到请求和响应
that code is run and we see the requests and responses
所以本质上我们只是视觉上的
so in essence we're just visually
测试，我在这里使用空中报价
testing and I'm using air quotes here
每个请求都有效
that each request works
你可能猜到了
and as you might guess
有更好的测试方法
there's a better way to do testing
当我们使用 mix 创建一个新的 elixir 项目时
when we created a new elixir project using mix
新的服务组合足够大胆
new service mix was presumptuous enough to
还生成一个测试目录
also generate a test directory
它里面有两个文件
and it has two files in it
测试助手 exs 和服务测试 exs
test helper exs and service test exs
测试文件是长生不老药脚本
the test files are elixir scripts
这就是性延伸
that's the sex extension
这意味着它们不必被编译
which means they don't have to be compiled
在他们跑步之前
before their run
如果我们查看测试助手
and if we look in test helper
好吧，我们看到它开始了
well we see that it starts
ex unit 和 ex unit 是 Elixir 内置的
ex unit and ex unit is elixir's built in
测试框架
test framework
那么如果我们看看调查测试
then if we have a look in survey test
好吧，有一个模块叫做调查测试
well there's a module called survey test
第一行说使用单位案例
and this first line says use ex unit case
使用添加测试功能或行为
use adds the testing functionality or behavior
在这个 ex unit case 模块中定义
that's defined in this ex unit case module
并将该行为添加到当前模块
and it adds that behavior to the current module
这是我们的调查测试
which is our survey test
第二行是这个
the 2nd line is this
停靠测试，我们将在一分钟内回到那个
dock test and we'll come back to that in just a minute
然后我们有定义测试的测试宏
then we have the testing macro which defines a test
然后有一个字符串的描述
and then there's a description as a string
和一段代码
and a block of code
然后在代码块内
and then inside of the block of code
我们陈述我们的期望
we state our expectations
使用这个断言宏
using this assert macro
只是测试这个表达是真的
was just test that this expression is truth
所以我们断言 1+1 等于 2
so we're asserting that 1+1 equals two
assert 的反义词叫做 refute
the opposite of assert is something called refute
所以我们可以反驳 2+1 等于 2
so we could refute that 2+1 equals two
因为那不是真的
because that's not true
通常这些
and generally these
两个宏都是
two macros are all
你需要做测试
you need to do testing
因为你要么会断言
because you're either going to assert that
某事是真的
something's true
或者你要反驳某事
or you're going to refute something
好吧，我现在要摆脱这个
all right I'm going to get rid of this for now
所以让我们继续运行这个测试
so let's go ahead and run this test
我在调查目录中
I'm in the survey directory
我们使用
and we run the test by using
混合测试，然后我们给它测试文件的名称
mix test and then we give it the name of the test file
所以它会是
so it's going to be
测试调查测试前
test survey test ex
毫不奇怪它成功了
and no surprise it succeeds
现在
now
让我们让它失败只是为了看看输出如何变化
let's make it fail just to see how the output changes
所以我们断言 1+1 等于
so we'll assert that 1+1 equals
三
three
再次运行测试
run the test again
你在这里向上滚动一点
you scroll up a little bit here
断言宏的好处是
well what's nice about the assert macro is
它内省代码
it introspects the code
给我们一些有用的反馈
to give us some helpful feedback
它向我们展示了在这里失败的断言
it shows us the assertion that failed right here
这是期望值二
this is the expected value two
然后这是实际值三
and then this is the actual value three
很酷，所以让我们继续把它改回
cool so let's go ahead and change it back to a
通过状态
passing state
我们去吧
there we go
所以我们不要编写自己的单元测试
so let's not write our own unit test
帮助我们开始
to help us get started
让我们复制这段代码
let's copy this code
然后我们可以为我们的解析器创建一个测试用例
and then we can create a test case for our parser
命名解析器下划线测试
named parser underscore test
我将粘贴我们拥有的代码
and I'll just paste in the code that we have
我们将把模块从
and we're going to change the module from
调查测试到解析器测试
survey test to parser test
我还将更改此文档测试以服务解析器
I'm also going to change this doc test to serve parser
我们会在一分钟内回到那个
and we'll come back to that in a minute
我们还需要在解析器中使用别名
we also need to alias in the parser
因为这就是我们要测试的
since that's what we're going to test
那么我们应该在解析器中测试什么
so what should we test in the parser
好吧，让我们看看解析器 ex
well let's have a look at that in parser ex
在我们结束兴趣之前
well before we get to our end to interest
让我们向他们展示两种编写单元测试的方法
let's show them two ways to write unit tests
是的，我们有一些递归
yeah we've got some recursion going
在这里，当我们解析标题时
on here when we're parsing the headers
所以让我们为这些函数编写一个单元测试
so let's write a unit test for these functions
你会记得这个功能
you'll remember this function
它需要一个
it takes a
头部和尾部的标题行列表
list of header lines that's the head and the tail
然后我们要解析那些
and then we want to parse those
进入包含键值对的映射，所以
into a map that contains key value pairs so
这将是标题
it'll be the headers
所以我们可以为此编写一个测试
so we can write a test for that
回到解析器测试
come back over to parser test
在此处更改描述
change the description here
解析头字段列表
parses a list of header fields
进入地图
into a map
摆脱这个，让我们设置一些标题行
get rid of this so let's set up some header lines
这将是一个看起来像这样的列表
it's going to be a list that looks like this
标头 a 的值可能为 1
the header a might have a value of one
然后标题 b 的值可能为 2
and then the header b might have a value of two
现在实际的标题有
now the actual headers have
不同的键和值，但 a one 和 b two 工作
different keys and values but a one and b two work
适合这里的测试
just fine for the test here
然后我们想改变这个
then we want to transform this
进入标题映射，我们通过调用解析器来做到这一点
into a map of headers and we do that by calling parser
解析标头
parse headers
我们传入标题行
we pass in the header lines
和一张这样的空地图
and an empty map like that
那么我们期望返回到标题看起来像什么
so what do we expect to return to headers to look like
好吧，我们可以使用 assert 宏并说我们断言
well we can use the assert macro and say we assert
标题等于地图
the headers equal a map
有一个键
that has a key of a
和一个值
and a value of one
和 b 的键
and a key of b
两个的值
the value of two
所以我们希望它解析这个行列表
so we expect it to parse this list of lines
成键值对
into key value pairs
如果我们把它保存起来
if we save that away
然后运行它，我们将像以前一样执行它
then to run it we'll do it just like before
除了我们要给它解析器测试
except we're going to give it parser test
看起来有效
it looks like it works
断言宏是
the assert macro is
实际上非常聪明地帮助你弄清楚
actually pretty smart about helping you figure out
为什么断言失败
why an assertion is failing
所以让我们说
so let's say
我们从我们的预期中删除一个关键值
that we remove one of the key values from our expected
map 然后我们重新运行我们的测试
map and then we rerun our tests
好吧，它失败了
well it fails
它告诉我们为什么我们看到左边的地图
and it tells us why we see the map on the left
与右边的地图不匹配
doesn't match the map on the right
因为左边那个
because the one on the left
也有一个键 b 和一个值二
also has a key b and a value of two
所以我们缺少一个关键值
so we're missing a key value
所以我就把它改回来，这样我们就可以通过测试了
so I'll just change that back so we have a passing test
好了，这是编写单元测试的一种方法
there we go so that's one way to write unit tests
但不是将它们放在单独的文件中
but instead of putting them in a separate file
我们可以写点东西
we can write something
称为文档测试
called doc tests
所以让我们回到我们的教区
so let's go back to our parish
我们已经测试过了
we've got this tested
但是这个解析的段落就在这里
but what about this parsed para right here
我将粘贴一些文档
I'm going to paste in a little bit of documentation
在顶部
at the top
我们已经知道如何使用
we already know how to use
在码头上记录一个函数的作用
at dock to document what a function does like this
包含以下示例也很有帮助
it's also helpful to include examples of
如何使用该功能
how to use the function
按照惯例
and by convention
这些示例显示在这样的 ix 会话中
those examples are shown in an ix session like this
现在
now
这个配色方案有点难看
this is a bit difficult to see with this color scheme
所以我只是不寻常的这些
so i'm just going to uncommon these
一分钟以获得不同的颜色
for a minute to get a different color
现在首先要注意的是我们写
now the first thing to note is that we write
长生不老药文档
elixir documentation
使用降价
using markdown
你注意到这里的双重哈希
you notice this double hash here
这将产生一个 h 2
that's going to generate an h two
你也会注意到我们在这里的代码
and you also notice that the code that we have up here
对于键和值
for keys and values
进入单个反引号内
goes inside of single back ticks
然后这部分被称为讲解员
and then this part is called the docent
它基本上是一组期望
and it's basically a set of expectations
或关于我们的代码如何工作的断言
or assertions about how our code is intended to work
所以如果我们有一个看起来像这样的参数字符串
so if we have a param string that looks like this
然后我们调用serve parser pars para
and then we call serve parser pars para
这是它的第一个参数
this is the first parameter to it
然后第二个参数是我们的参数字符串
and then the second parameter is our param string
好吧，我们期望什么
well what do we expect
好吧，我们希望 ix 返回一个看起来像这样的地图
well we expect ix to return a map that looks like this
它从这里获取名称和类型
it took the name and the type from here
并将其放入地图中
and put it inside of a map
然后如果我们用 parse para 调用
and then if we call parse para with
多部分表单数据作为第一个参数
multipart form data as the first parameter
param string 是第二个参数
and param string is the second parameter
好吧，我们不处理
well we don't handle
这种格式，所以我们希望回到
this format so we expect to get back in
空地图
empty map
现在如果我们能跑起来岂不是很酷
now wouldn't it be cool if we could run
这些例子和检查
these examples and check
函数返回的实际值
that the actual value returned by the function
匹配注释中显示的值
matches the values shown in the comment
想象一下，这正是这条讲解路线
imagine that well that's exactly what this docent line
在解析器测试中完成
over in parser test does
这是一个寻找的宏
it's a macro that looks for
本模块调查解析器中的讲解员
docents in this module survey parser
如果它找到了讲解员，那么它会为他们生成测试
and if it finds docent then it generates tests for them
所以因为我们已经有了这条线
so because we already have this line
我们在这里进行了码头测试
and we've got this dock test over here
我只需要
I just need to
以应有的方式发表评论
comment this the way it should be
所以这是一个实际的码头测试
so it's an actual dock test
像这样把它保存起来
like that save it away
现在如果我们来到这里再次运行解析器测试
now if we come down here and run parser test again
现在我们有两个测试
well now we have two tests
我们通常编写的单元测试之一
one of the unit tests we wrote conventionally
并且其中一项测试是从
and one of the tests got generated from
这个码头测试
this dock test
现在只是为了表明这是一个实际的测试
now just to show that this is an actual test
让它失败
let's make it fail
我会将这种类型更改为颜色
I'll change this type to a color
果然失败了
and sure enough it fails
就像任何其他单元测试一样
just like any other unit test would
所以让我们继续把它改回来
so let's go ahead and change that back
这真的很酷的是我们
what's really cool about this is we
一直都知道dock test中的例子是
always know that the examples in the dock test are
最新的，他们从不撒谎，这是你的事
up to date and they never lie which is something you
总是希望在文档中
always hope for in documentation
但不要总是得到
but don't always get
所以现在我们有两个测试文件
so now we have two test files
我们可以一口气运行这些测试
and we can run those tests in one swoop
我们只是通过使用来做到这一点
we just do that by using
混合测试而不给它一个文件名
mix test and not giving it a file name
我们看到我们有三个测试
we see that we have three tests
我们已经进行了解析器测试，然后进行了调查测试
we've got our parser tests and then survey tests
混合测试所做的只是在
and what mix test did is it just looked in the
测试目录在这里
test directory here
它找到了所有以下划线测试结尾的文件
and it found all the files ending in underscore tests
前它继续运行那些
ex and it went ahead and ran those
现在我们知道如何编写测试了
now that we know how to write tests
让我们回到最初的目标
let's return to our original goal
这是要转换
which was to convert
此代码位于句柄模块的底部
this code at the bottom of the handle module
进入自动化测试
into automated tests
让我们从删除这些开始
let's start by deleting these
因为我们不想要这个
because we don't want this
当我们运行我们的应用程序时执行的代码
code executing when we run our app
所以我们要深入到最底层
so we're just going to go down to the very bottom
在这里抓住所有这些东西
grab all this stuff here
到那里并把它消灭掉
to there and zap it out
我要创建一个新的测试文件
I'm going to create a new test file
测试目录下
under the test directory
它将被称为 handler test exs
it's going to be called handler test exs
我现在要粘贴我们的第一个结束测试
and I'm going to paste in our first end end test now
不用担心在这个测试中输入
don't worry about typing in this test
你真的会找到它
you'll actually find it
以及代码包中的所有其他测试
as well as all the other tests in the code bundle
它被称为处理程序测试
it's called handler test
又是这条使用线
there's this use line again
然后我们有这条导入线
and then we have this import line
我们在这里要做的是导入这个
what we're going to do here is import this
句柄函数
handle function
只是为了在这个模块内部很容易使用
just so it's easy to use inside of this module
然后我们在这里使用我们的测试宏
then we use our test macro here
我们的描述是
and our description is
这是为了获得一些狂野的东西
this is for a get of wild things
我们有我们的代码块
we've got our code block
所以我们在代码块中所做的是
so what we do inside the code block is
我们建立了一个请求
we set up a request
使用听码头
using a hear dock
我们通过请求
we pass the request
进入我们的句柄函数，这是服务处理程序句柄
into our handle function this is serve handler handle
我们得到回复
we get back a response
然后我们将使用 assert 宏
and then we're going to use the assert macro
断言该响应等于
to assert that that response equals
另一个听到码头，这是我们的回应
another hear dock which is our response
现在你可能想知道
now you might be wondering
行尾的这些字符是什么
what's with these characters at the end of the lines
以及http规范
well the http spec
实际上需要这些行结束
actually requires these lines to end
在作为反斜杠 r 的回车换行符中
in a carriage return line feed which is backslash r
反斜杠 n
backslash n
现在发坞隐含地给了我们反斜杠 n
now the hair dock implicitly gives us the backslash n
在每一行的末尾
at the end of each line
但我们必须明确添加反斜杠 r
but we have to explicitly add the backslash r
所以你会在这些行的末尾看到
so you see that at the end of these lines
以同样的方式
in the same way
规范还要求
the spec also requires
响应行上的反斜杠 r 反斜杠 n
backslash r backslash n on the response lines
所以我们在这里添加了这些
so we've added those here
现在这有点
now this is a bit
迂腐，但消息正文在此处的最后一行
pedantic but the message body this last line here
不必有反斜杠 r
doesn't have to have a backslash r
所以你在那里看不到一个
so you don't see one there
我们不希望这些早点妨碍
we didn't want these to get in the way earlier
他们看起来有点讨厌
they do kind of look obnoxious
但稍后会从浏览器发送请求
but a bit later will send requests from a browser
他们将采用这种格式
and they'll be in this format
所以我们现在不妨考虑这些角色
so we might as well account for these characters now
所以让我们看看这个测试是否有效
so let's see if this test works
混合测试
mix test
处理程序测试前
handler test ex
看起来我们有问题
and it looks like we have a problem
如果我们在这里向上滚动
if we scroll up here
虽然我们看到右侧值不匹配
while we see no match the right side value
得到狂野的东西
get wild things
注意我们看到这些
and notice we see these
反斜杠 r 反斜杠在此处结束
backslash r backslash ends throughout here
因为这就是我们的要求
because that's what our request has
但这不是我们的解析器所期望的
but that's not what our parser's expecting
所以我们回到解析器
so we go back over to the parser
这里的最高点
the very top here
我们分开
we split on
斜线很好，这实际上是
slash n well this is actually going to be
反斜杠 r 反斜杠 n
backslash r backslash n
将顶部与婴儿车字符串分开
that separates the top from the pram strings
以同样的方式
in the same way
所有最上面的行都有一个反斜杠 r 反斜杠 n
all the top lines will have a backslash r backslash n
以便修复解析器但在处理程序中
so that fixes the parser but over in the handler
我们还需要改变这个格式响应函数
we also need to change this format response function
包括反斜杠 r
to include backslash r
在这些行的末尾
at the end of these lines
现在我们的测试应该通过了
and now our test should pass
下来这里
come down here
再次运行它，果然他们通过了
run it again sure enough they pass
已经只有七个测试要写了
already so only seven more tests to write
准备好你的手指
get your fingers ready
只是在开玩笑
just kidding
我们不会让你受苦
we're not going to make you suffer through that
我们只是要一次又一次地粘贴它们
we're just going to paste them in and again
您可以在代码包中找到所有测试
you can find all the tests in the code bundle
这是我们刚刚编写的测试
so here's the test that we just wrote
然后我们在它下面粘贴了一些测试
and then we pasted some tests beneath it
所以这是一个用于获得斜线熊的
so here's one for get slash bears
我们设置了请求
we set up the request
我们调用句柄得到响应
we call handle get a response to that
我做了这个有点不同
and I did this one a little bit differently
注意我说预期响应等于
notice I say expected response equals
然后我们有一个听码头
and then we have a hear dock
然后我们有我们期望的标题
and then we have the headers we would expect
然后是内容
and then the content
记住从模板生成
remembers generated from a template
这就是模板生成的所有内容
so this is all that template generated content
因为那个模板可以有不同的
and because that template can have different
里面的空白
white space in it
有时很难断言
and sometimes it's difficult to assert
基于空白
based on white space
我写了一个小函数
I wrote a little function down
下面称为删除右空间
below called remove right space
所以我们只在响应中调用删除空格
so we just call remove white space on the response
那应该等于
and that should equal
相当于我们预期的反应
the equivalent of our expected response
我们使用 assert 宏
and we use the assert macro
确保这是真的
to make sure that's true
并且所有其他测试都以类似的方式工作
and all the other tests work in a similar way
这里真的没有什么新鲜事
there's really nothing new here
如果只是一行
if it's just one line
像这样的回应
of a response like this
不是从模板生成的
that wasn't generated from a template
那么我只是在那个响应上使用断言
well then I just use assert on that response
但如果是模板生成的代码
but if it's template generated code
我使用这种去除空白的模式
I use this pattern of removing white space
但你可以看看这里，你会看到
but you can look through here and you'll see that
他们都遵循相似的风格
all of them follow the similar style
更好的是他们都应该通过
and better yet they should all pass
他们确实做到了
and indeed they do
但如果你滚动
but if you scroll
向上
up
你可能想知道这里的所有这些输出是怎么回事
you might wonder what's with all this output up here
好吧，如果你记得
well if you recall
我们在处理程序顶部的管道有插件
our pipeline at the top of handler has plugins
记录和跟踪请求
to log and track requests
这些功能在插件模块中
those functions are in the plugins module
他们使用 io 打印出警告信息
and they use io to print out a warning message
并将信息记录到控制台
and log information to the console
但也许我们
but perhaps we
只想打印这个
only want to print this
应用程序时的东西到控制台
stuff to the console when the app
在特定环境中运行
is running in a specific environment
是的 mix 实际上支持三种不同的环境
yeah mix actually supports three different environments
dev test 和 prod 是 production 的缩写
dev test and prod which is short for production
de 是默认值，当我们使用时它会切换到测试
de is the default and it switches to test when we use
混合测试
mix test
所以假设我们只想看到这个的输出
so suppose we only want to see the output of this
开发过程中的日志功能
log function during development
虽然我们可以改变这个
while we can change this around
并在此处将其更改为多行函数
and change it to a multiline function here
然后我们只希望这条线运行
and then we only want this line to run
在开发过程中
during development
所以我们可以在这里放一个 if 语句
so we can put an if statement around here
如果你可以打电话给 mix
if and you can call mix
end 将返回当前的混音环境
end that will return the current mix environment
如果它等于 dev
if it equals dev
我们会继续打印出来
we'll go ahead and print that out
否则它不会记住
otherwise it won't and remember
因为这个日志在管道中起作用
because this log functions in a pipeline
我们总是需要返回 con
we always need to return co n
哦
oh
我总是忘记在 if 结尾加上露水
and I always forget to add the dew at the end of an if
只是旧习惯
just old habit
这样就可以处理日志
so that takes care of log
这里的跟踪功能怎么样
what about this track function up here
好吧，假设我们要跟踪四人之四
well let's say we want to track four of fours
在开发和生产中
in development and in production
但不在测试中
but not in test
所以我们可以在这里做的是说
so what we can do here is say
如果混合结束不等于测试做
if mix end does not equal test do
把它放在那个 if 条件里面
put that inside of that if condition
然后确保总是返回 co 和 v
and then make sure to always return co and v
如果我们把它保存起来
if we save that away
并运行我们的测试，我们应该得到更清晰的输出
and run our test we should get a lot cleaner output
我们去吧
there we go
如果我们很好地运行我们所有的测试
and if we run all of our test well
我们确实应该全面绿色
we should have green across the board indeed we do